if you don't know what it is it's a
wonderful tool that allows us to
basically organize our life we can use
it to write down our notes create task
force to do lists wikis documentation
pages calendars collaborate on themes
among many other things but what many
people actually don't know is that
notion has a really sweet api that we
can use to access notion with our code
thanks to this api we can use notion as
our cms or content management system and
even as a database for our data
basically we can use the notion website
to input the data and later we can use
the notion api to consume this data and
display it however we want to and that
is exactly what we're going to do today
on today's video we are going to see how
we can use notion and its api as our
admin panel and database for a web
application to get started we are going
to go to notion and after creating an
account or logging in we are going to
create a table database we are going to
choose a name for our database and then
we're going to get started entering the
data what we're building today is a web
app that we can use to find good places
to work from in seoul
for this we're going to add three
columns to our notion database the name
of the place the address of the place
and then a link to either the website of
the place or maybe the map url after
that is done we're going to head to
notion that so slash my integrations to
get an api key we will click on create
new integration and after giving it a
name and pressing submit we will see our
api key now we need to copy this key
because we're going to need it later
after that is done we're going to go
back to our notion database and we're
going to click on share we're going to
share the database with the integration
we just created and that is it
now our api key has access to that
database so we are now ready to call the
notion api but before we do that we have
to know that we cannot call the notion
api from a browser this is of course for
security reasons so this is why we need
to call it from a server if we go to the
notion api documentation we can see a
list of all the actions we can perform
we will click on the one that we are
interested on and that is query a
database if we look at the documentation
we are going to see that there are two
options on how we can call this api
route one is with the official notion
javascript sdk and the other one is with
a simple http call with authorization
and notion version headers all we need
for this request is the api secret that
we received before and the id of our
database the id of the database is on
the url bar when you are in the database
page in the notion website to call this
api like we said you need a server and
as a server you can use whatever you
want but today we're going to use
klausler workers which is in my opinion
one of the easiest ways to create a
serverless api and the code is also very
easy to understand as well for this
video we are not going to be using the
sdk of notion because i want you to be
able to do this in whatever language you
want maybe you have a server on python
or in java so for this we're going to
use the rest api of notion which is just
a url that we have to hit the code of
the cluster workers is going to be on
javascript which is very easy to
understand and the way it works is like
this when our api receives a get request
we will hit the notion api with the id
of our page and we will send the headers
with our secret token and the notion api
version when we receive this data from
the notion api we're going to send it
back to the user that is calling our api
so now let's take a look at the data
that we receive from notion now all the
rows in our notion database are actually
a page in notion so what we receive when
we query our database is an array or a
list of pages as you can see each page
has the columns that we defined before
now all we have to do is paint this data
in our ui for this step we can use any
framework we want i in my case i'm going
to use next.js with tailwind css but
whatever you use is completely fine and
we are done as you can see the data that
we wrote in our notion database is now
being displayed in our custom made ui
all we had to do was write a tiny little
server code and the rest was just css
our users won't be able to even imagine
that what they are looking at is a page
powered by notion as a backend to finish
with a bank what i want to do now is
allow the users to upload data to the
notion database but from my website if
we go back to the notion documentation
we will see that there is a rest api
endpoint that we can use to create a
page and we can also link that page to
our notion database now all we have to
do is make a form for people to submit a
place to our database and push that data
all the way to the notion api this is
because remember we cannot call the
notion api from our browser we have to
call it from our api the code to send
the data to the notion api is very
similar to the one that we used when we
wanted to get data from the notion api
we have to hit a notion api url with the
authentication headers and we need to
specify the parent of the page which
will be the id of the database and then
the properties which are the name of the
columns in our database and now it's the
moment of truth let's go back to our
application and submit the form
after we do that let's go back to our
notion database and see if the data was
uploaded and as you can see it's there
we are using notion as our database and
our admin panel how cool is that this
makes the prototyping of projects so
much easier and because of notions super
cool team collaboration features we can
invite non-developers to this notion
database and they can input the data
there without touching a single line of
code this notion api unlocks a lot of
new possibilities this current stack
will take us very far away i believe but
one thing to notice is that notion api
has a limit of 3 requests per second if
the project that we built today grew
bigger than that we would have to start
thinking about adding a caching layer in
front of our api still this is more than
enough to get our side projects up and
running in record time thank you so much
to notion for sponsoring this video we
absolutely love notion here at nomad
colors and now with this api i'm already
thinking of all the cool things that i
want to build thank you for watching as
always let me know what do you think of
this video in the comments i'm going to
be looking at them right now stay
healthy stay free stay happy eat kimchi
see you in the next one bye